Jason M Schwarz

Data Scientist, Healthcare SME

Linkedin.com/in/JasonSchwarzPT



Schwarz.Jason.Data@gmail.com



Jason-Schwarz-Portfolio



github.com/oto235



512.569.4688



Austin, TX



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, R, SQL

PyTorch, Torchvision,

Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Scikit Learn

Exploratory and Statistical Data Analysis

Logistic, Linear Regression

Large Language Models

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Data Science, The University of Texas at Austin, 2023, **3.9**/4.0

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, Coursera, 2022

Doctor of Physical Therapy, Texas Woman's University, 2014, 4.0/4.0

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, The University of Texas at Austin

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Recently graduated (master's) data scientist with 2+ years of experience with predictive modeling, statistical data analysis, and data visualization. Health care leader with 10+ years of experience as a home health physical therapist building teams and tools to save time, improve health care, and increase financial metrics. Proficient in Python.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Data Scientist and Programmer, 2021 - Present

- Write and maintain Python scripts to perform medical record data entry.
 - Increases therapist productivity by 25%
 - Improves documentation accuracy by estimated 10%:
 - Uses pre-loaded physician and company variables.
 - Allows short-term memory dump immediately after visits.
- Perform exploratory data analysis and provide recommendations.
 - Ex: Healing Hugs

Data Science Graduate Student, UT Austin, 2022 - 2023

- Learning Facilitator for Deep Learning course (400+ students)
 - Provided biweekly virtual office hours.
 - Monitored and answered student discussion board.
 - Graded final reports.
- Courses taken:

Regression Causal Inference and Design Principles
Optimization Design Structures and Algorithms
Deep Learning Natural Language Processing
Machine Learning Advanced Predictive Models
Data Visualization Probability and Statistics

Rehab Team Lead, Physical Therapist, Various Home Health Agencies, 2014 - Present

- Significantly moved the needle on various financial and clinical metrics.
- Created multiple tools to improve clinical experience and time management.
- Established a network of healthcare providers in the greater Austin area.
- Attained company-top-tier Rehab Clinical Ladder Level IV (2020)
- Peer voted as the Regional **Therapist of the Year** (2019)
- Board-certified geriatric clinical specialist

Navy SEAL, United States Navy

- Received Joint Service Achievement Medal, Good Conduct Medal, and more.
- Honorably discharged.